<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<MedlinePlus-document>
<record>
<header>
<identifier>https://medlineplus.gov/alcoholismandalcoholabuse.html</identifier>
</header>
<metadata xmlns="http://example.org/myapp/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://example.org/myapp/schema.xsd">
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="es">Abuso de alcohol</dc:title>
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="es">Emborracharse</dc:title>
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="en">Substance Abuse</dc:title>
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="en">Drinking</dc:title>
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="en">Alcohol Dependence</dc:title>
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="en">Alcohol Withdrawal</dc:title>
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="en">Binge Drinking</dc:title>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:language>spa</dc:language>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:title xml:lang="es">Alcoholismo y abuso de alcohol</dc:title>
<dc:title xml:lang="en">Alcoholism and Alcohol Abuse</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>National Library of Medicine</dc:publisher>
<dc:relation type="IsPartOf">Substance Abuse Problems</dc:relation>
<dc:date type="created">2002-07-21</dc:date>
<dc:date type="modified">2018-02-14</dc:date>
<dc:identifier type="URL" xml:lang="es">https://medlineplus.gov/spanish/alcoholismandalcoholabuse.html</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier type="URL" xml:lang="en">https://medlineplus.gov/alcoholismandalcoholabuse.html</dc:identifier>
<dc:description xml:lang="es">Para la mayoría de los adultos, el consumo moderado de alcohol probablemente no es peligroso. Sin embargo, cerca de 18 millones de adultos en Estados Unidos tienen trastorno por el consumo de alcohol. Esto quiere decir que sus hábitos de consumo causan angustia y daños. Esto incluye alcoholismo y abuso del alcohol. El alcoholismo o dependencia de alcohol es una enfermedad que causa: Ansia: Una fuerte necesidad de beber Pérdida de control: Incapacidad para dejar de beber una vez que se comenzó Dependencia física: Síntomas de abstinencia Tolerancia: La necesidad de beber cada vez más cantidad de alcohol para sentir el mismo efecto Con el abuso del alcohol, usted no es físicamente dependiente pero tiene un problema serio. El consumo de alcohol puede causar problemas en el hogar, el trabajo o la escuela. Puede ponerlo en situaciones peligrosas, o llevarlo a tener problemas legales o sociales. Otro problema común es el consumo excesivo de alcohol, definido como beber cerca de cinco o más bebidas en dos horas para los hombres y cuatro o más bebidas en dos horas para mujeres. Beber demasiado alcohol es peligroso. El consumo excesivo de alcohol puede aumentar el riesgo de ciertos tipos de cáncer. Puede conducir a enfermedades del hígado como hígado graso y cirrosis. También puede causar daño al cerebro ya otros órganos. Beber durante el embarazo puede dañar a su bebé. El alcohol también aumenta el riesgo de muerte por accidentes de tránsito, lesiones, homicidios y suicidios. Usted puede tener un trastorno por consumo de alcohol si contesta afirmativamente a dos o más de las siguientes preguntas. En el último año, usted: ¿Terminó bebiendo más o por más tiempo más de lo que había planeado? ¿Quiso reducir o dejar de beber, o trató de hacerlo y no pudo? ¿Pasó mucho tiempo bebiendo, o recuperándose de beber mucho? ¿Tuvo una fuerte necesidad de beber? ¿Encontró que beber, o sentirse mal por beber, a menudo interfirió con su vida familiar, trabajo o escuela? ¿Siguió bebiendo a pesar de que estaba causándole problemas con su familia o amigos? ¿Dejó o disminuyó actividades que disfrutaba para beber? ¿Se puso en situaciones peligrosas mientras bebía o después de beber? Algunos ejemplos son conducir borracho y tener relaciones sexuales de alto riesgo ¿Siguió bebiendo aunque le hiciera sentir deprimido o ansioso? ¿O cuando agravaba otro problema de salud? ¿Debió beber más y más para sentir los efectos del alcohol? ¿Sentía síntomas de abstinencia cuando se le estaba pasando el efecto del alcohol? Los síntomas incluyen problemas para dormir, temblores, irritabilidad, ansiedad, depresión, inquietud, náuseas y sudores. En casos severos, usted podría tener fiebre, convulsiones o alucinaciones Si usted tiene alguno de estos síntomas, su consumo ya puede ser motivo de preocupación. Cuantos más síntomas tenga, más grave es el problema. Si cree que podría tener un trastorno por consumo de alcohol, consulte a su proveedor de atención médica para una evaluación. Su proveedor puede ayudarle a hacer un plan de tratamiento, recetar medicamentos y, si es necesario, darle referencias de tratamiento. NIH: Instituto Nacional sobre el Abuso del Alcohol y Alcoholismo</dc:description>
<dc:description xml:lang="en">For most adults, moderate alcohol use is probably not harmful. However, about 18 million adult Americans have an alcohol use disorder (AUD). This means that their drinking causes distress and harm. It includes alcoholism and alcohol abuse. Alcoholism, or alcohol dependence, is a disease that causes Craving - a strong need to drink Loss of control - not being able to stop drinking once you've started Physical dependence - withdrawal symptoms Tolerance - the need to drink more alcohol to feel the same effect With alcohol abuse, you are not physically dependent, but you still have a serious problem. The drinking may cause problems at home, work, or school. It may cause you to put yourself in dangerous situations, or lead to legal or social problems. Another common problem is binge drinking. It is drinking about five or more drinks in two hours for men. For women, it is about four or more drinks in two hours. Too much alcohol is dangerous. Heavy drinking can increase the risk of certain cancers. It can cause damage to the liver, brain, and other organs. Drinking during pregnancy can harm your baby. Alcohol also increases the risk of death from car crashes, injuries, homicide, and suicide. You may have an AUD if you can answer yes to two or more of these questions: In the past year, have you Ended up drinking more or for a longer time than you had planned to? Wanted to cut down or stop drinking, or tried to, but couldn't? Spent a lot of your time drinking, or recovering from drinking? Felt a strong need to drink? Found that drinking - or being sick from drinking - often interfered with your family life, job, or school? Kept drinking even though it was causing trouble with your family or friends? Given up or cut back on activities that you enjoyed just so you could drink? Gotten into dangerous situations while drinking or after drinking? Some examples are driving drunk and having unsafe sex. Kept drinking even though it was making you feel depressed or anxious? Or when it was adding to another health problem? Had to drink more and more to feel the effects of the alcohol? Had withdrawal symptoms when the alcohol was wearing off? They include trouble sleeping, shakiness, irritability, anxiety, depression, restlessness, nausea, and sweating. In severe cases, you could have a fever, seizures, or hallucinations. If you have any of these symptoms, your drinking may already be a cause for concern. The more symptoms you have, the more serious the problem is. If you think you might have an AUD, see your health care provider for an evaluation. Your provider can help make a treatment plan, prescribe medicines, and if needed, give you treatment referrals. NIH: National Institute on Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism</dc:description>
<dc:subject dcterms="mesh">Alcoholism</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Alcoholismo y abuso de alcohol</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Abuso de alcohol</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Emborracharse</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Alcoholism and Alcohol Abuse</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Substance Abuse</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Drinking</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Alcohol Dependence</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Alcohol Withdrawal</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Binge Drinking</dc:subject>
</metadata>
</record>
</MedlinePlus-document>
