<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<MedlinePlus-document>
<record>
<header>
<identifier>https://medlineplus.gov/atherosclerosis.html</identifier>
</header>
<metadata xmlns="http://example.org/myapp/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://example.org/myapp/schema.xsd">
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="es">Arterias obstruidas</dc:title>
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="en">Hardening of the Arteries</dc:title>
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="en">Arteriosclerosis</dc:title>
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="en">Plaque, Atherosclerotic</dc:title>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:language>spa</dc:language>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:title xml:lang="es">Arterioesclerosis</dc:title>
<dc:title xml:lang="en">Atherosclerosis</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>National Library of Medicine</dc:publisher>
<dc:relation type="IsPartOf">Blood, Heart and Circulation</dc:relation>
<dc:date type="created">2010-04-13</dc:date>
<dc:date type="modified">2018-01-08</dc:date>
<dc:identifier type="URL" xml:lang="es">https://medlineplus.gov/spanish/atherosclerosis.html</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier type="URL" xml:lang="en">https://medlineplus.gov/atherosclerosis.html</dc:identifier>
<dc:description xml:lang="es">La arterioesclerosis es una afección en la cual placa se acumula dentro de las arterias. Placa es una sustancia pegajosa compuesta de grasa, colesterol, calcio y otras sustancias que se encuentran en la sangre. Con el tiempo, esta placa se endurece y angosta las arterias. Eso limita el flujo de sangre rica en oxígeno. La arterioesclerosis puede llevar a problemas graves como: Enfermedad de las arterias coronarias. Estas arterias llevan sangre a su corazón. Cuando se bloquean, usted puede sufrir una angina de pecho o un ataque cardíaco Enfermedades de las arterias carótidas. Estas arterias llevan sangre a su cerebro. Cuando se bloquean, usted puede sufrir un ataque cerebral Enfermedad arterial periférica. Estas arterias están en sus brazos, piernas y pelvis. Cuando se bloquean, usted puede sufrir adormecimiento, dolor y a veces infecciones En general, la arterioesclerosis no presenta síntomas hasta que una arteria se estrecha demasiado o por completo. Mucha gente no sabe que la sufre hasta que tiene una emergencia médica. Un examen físico, diagnóstico por imágenes y otro tipo de pruebas diagnósticas puede revelar si usted la sufre. Los tratamientos pueden desacelerar el avance de acumulación de placa. Su médico puede también recomendar procedimientos como la angioplastía para abrir las arterias o cirugía en las arterias coronarias o carótidas. Un cambio en el estilo de vida también puede ayudar. Esto incluye seguir una dieta sana, hacer ejercicio con regularidad, mantener un peso saludable, dejar de fumar y manejar el estrés. NIH: Instituto Nacional del Corazón, los Pulmones y la Sangre</dc:description>
<dc:description xml:lang="en">Atherosclerosis is a disease in which plaque builds up inside your arteries. Plaque is a sticky substance made up of fat, cholesterol, calcium, and other substances found in the blood. Over time, plaque hardens and narrows your arteries. That limits the flow of oxygen-rich blood to your body. Atherosclerosis can lead to serious problems, including Coronary artery disease. These arteries supply blood to your heart. When they are blocked, you can suffer angina or a heart attack. Carotid artery disease. These arteries supply blood to your brain. When they are blocked you can suffer a stroke. Peripheral arterial disease. These arteries are in your arms, legs and pelvis. When they are blocked, you can suffer from numbness, pain and sometimes infections. Atherosclerosis usually doesn't cause symptoms until it severely narrows or totally blocks an artery. Many people don't know they have it until they have a medical emergency. A physical exam, imaging, and other diagnostic tests can tell if you have it. Medicines can slow the progress of plaque buildup. Your doctor may also recommend procedures such as angioplasty to open the arteries, or surgery on the coronary or carotid arteries. Lifestyle changes can also help. These include following a healthy diet, getting regular exercise, maintaining a healthy weight, quitting smoking, and managing stress. NIH: National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute</dc:description>
<dc:subject dcterms="mesh">Atherosclerosis</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Arterioesclerosis</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Arterias obstruidas</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Atherosclerosis</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Hardening of the Arteries</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Arteriosclerosis</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Plaque</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Atherosclerotic</dc:subject>
</metadata>
</record>
</MedlinePlus-document>
