<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<MedlinePlus-document>
<record>
<header>
<identifier>https://medlineplus.gov/bonemarrowtransplantation.html</identifier>
</header>
<metadata xmlns="http://example.org/myapp/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://example.org/myapp/schema.xsd">
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="es">Médula ósea, Trasplante</dc:title>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:language>spa</dc:language>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:title xml:lang="es">Trasplante de médula ósea</dc:title>
<dc:title xml:lang="en">Bone Marrow Transplantation</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>National Library of Medicine</dc:publisher>
<dc:relation type="IsPartOf">Immune System</dc:relation>
<dc:relation type="IsPartOf">Transplantation and Donation</dc:relation>
<dc:date type="created">2002-07-21</dc:date>
<dc:date type="modified">2018-01-31</dc:date>
<dc:identifier type="URL" xml:lang="es">https://medlineplus.gov/spanish/bonemarrowtransplantation.html</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier type="URL" xml:lang="en">https://medlineplus.gov/bonemarrowtransplantation.html</dc:identifier>
<dc:description xml:lang="es">La médula ósea es el tejido esponjoso dentro de algunos de sus huesos, como la cadera y el fémur. Contiene células inmaduras llamadas células madre. Las células madre pueden desarrollarse hasta ser glóbulos rojos que transportan oxígeno a su cuerpo, glóbulos blancos que combaten las infecciones y plaquetas que ayudan a la coagulación de la sangre. Un trasplante de médula ósea es un procedimiento que reemplaza las células madre defectuosas de la médula ósea de una persona. Los médicos utilizan estos trasplantes para tratar a personas con ciertas enfermedades, como: Leucemia Enfermedades graves de la sangre como las talasemias, anemia aplásica y anemia falciforme Mieloma múltiple Ciertas enfermedades inmunitarias Antes de someterse a un trasplante, usted necesita someterse a altas dosis de quimioterapia y posiblemente radiación. Esto destruye las células madre dañadas en la médula ósea. También suprime el sistema inmunitario del cuerpo para que no ataque a las nuevas células madre después del trasplante. En algunos casos, usted puede donar sus propias células madre de médula ósea con antelación. Las células se guardan y se usan más adelante. También puede obtener células madre de un donante. El donante puede ser un miembro de su familia o una persona no relacionada. El trasplante de médula ósea tiene riesgos graves. Algunas complicaciones pueden ser potencialmente mortales. Sin embargo, para algunas personas es la mejor esperanza para una cura o una vida más larga. NIH: Instituto Nacional del Corazón, los Pulmones y la Sangre</dc:description>
<dc:description xml:lang="en">Bone marrow is the spongy tissue inside some of your bones, such as your hip and thigh bones. It contains immature cells, called stem cells. The stem cells can develop into red blood cells, which carry oxygen throughout the body, white blood cells, which fight infections, and platelets, which help the blood to clot. A bone marrow transplant is a procedure that replaces a person's faulty bone marrow stem cells. Doctors use these transplants to treat people with certain diseases, such as Leukemia Severe blood diseases such as thalassemias, aplastic anemia, and sickle cell anemia Multiple myeloma Certain immune deficiency diseases Before you have a transplant, you need to get high doses of chemotherapy and possibly radiation. This destroys the faulty stem cells in your bone marrow. It also suppresses your body's immune system so that it won't attack the new stem cells after the transplant. In some cases, you can donate your own bone marrow stem cells in advance. The cells are saved and then used later on. Or you can get cells from a donor. The donor might be a family member or unrelated person. Bone marrow transplantation has serious risks. Some complications can be life-threatening. But for some people, it is the best hope for a cure or a longer life. NIH: National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute</dc:description>
<dc:subject dcterms="mesh">Bone Marrow Transplantation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Trasplante de médula ósea</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Médula ósea</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Trasplante</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Bone Marrow Transplantation</dc:subject>
</metadata>
</record>
</MedlinePlus-document>
