<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<MedlinePlus-document>
<record>
<header>
<identifier>https://medlineplus.gov/familyissues.html</identifier>
</header>
<metadata xmlns="http://example.org/myapp/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://example.org/myapp/schema.xsd">
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="es">Familias entremezcladas</dc:title>
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="es">Familia, Asuntos</dc:title>
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="en">Stepfamilies</dc:title>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:language>spa</dc:language>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:title xml:lang="es">Asuntos familiares</dc:title>
<dc:title xml:lang="en">Family Issues</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>National Library of Medicine</dc:publisher>
<dc:relation type="IsPartOf">Social/Family Issues</dc:relation>
<dc:date type="created">2002-07-21</dc:date>
<dc:date type="modified">2018-01-10</dc:date>
<dc:identifier type="URL" xml:lang="es">https://medlineplus.gov/spanish/familyissues.html</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier type="URL" xml:lang="en">https://medlineplus.gov/familyissues.html</dc:identifier>
<dc:description xml:lang="es">Existen muchos tipos de familias. Algunas tienen padre y madre y otras tienen sólo uno de ellos. Algunas veces no hay padres y los abuelos crían a sus nietos. Algunos niños viven con familias sustitutas, adoptivas o políticas. Las familias son mucho más que grupos de personas que comparten los mismos genes o la misma dirección. Deben ser una fuente de apoyo y amor. Eso no significa que todos se lleven bien todo el tiempo. Los conflictos son parte de la vida familiar. Muchas cosas pueden conducir a conflictos, tales como enfermedades, discapacidades, adicciones, pérdida del empleo, dificultades en la escuela y problemas maritales. Escucharse y trabajar para resolver los conflictos es importante para fortalecer la familia.</dc:description>
<dc:description xml:lang="en">There are many kinds of families. Some have two parents, while others have a single parent. Sometimes there is no parent and grandparents raise grandchildren. Some children live in foster families, adoptive families, or in stepfamilies. Families are much more than groups of people who share the same genes or the same address. They should be a source of love and support. This does not mean that everyone gets along all the time. Conflicts are a part of family life. Many things can lead to conflict, such as illness, disability, addiction, job loss, school problems, and marital issues. Listening to each other and working to resolve conflicts are important in strengthening the family.</dc:description>
<dc:subject dcterms="mesh">Family</dc:subject>
<dc:subject dcterms="mesh">Interpersonal Relations</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Asuntos familiares</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Familias entremezcladas</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Familia</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Asuntos</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Family Issues</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Stepfamilies</dc:subject>
</metadata>
</record>
</MedlinePlus-document>
