<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<MedlinePlus-document>
<record>
<header>
<identifier>https://medlineplus.gov/fetalalcoholspectrumdisorders.html</identifier>
</header>
<metadata xmlns="http://example.org/myapp/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://example.org/myapp/schema.xsd">
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="es">Alcoholismo fetal, Síndrome de</dc:title>
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="es">Espectro alcohólico fetal, Trastornos del</dc:title>
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="es">Síndrome de alcoholismo fetal</dc:title>
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="es">TEAF</dc:title>
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="en">FAS</dc:title>
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="en">Fetal Alcohol Syndrome</dc:title>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:language>spa</dc:language>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:title xml:lang="es">Trastornos del espectro alcohólico fetal</dc:title>
<dc:title xml:lang="en">Fetal Alcohol Spectrum Disorders</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>National Library of Medicine</dc:publisher>
<dc:relation type="IsPartOf">Genetics/Birth Defects</dc:relation>
<dc:relation type="IsPartOf">Pregnancy and Reproduction</dc:relation>
<dc:relation type="IsPartOf">Substance Abuse Problems</dc:relation>
<dc:date type="created">2002-07-21</dc:date>
<dc:date type="modified">2017-08-28</dc:date>
<dc:identifier type="URL" xml:lang="es">https://medlineplus.gov/spanish/fetalalcoholspectrumdisorders.html</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier type="URL" xml:lang="en">https://medlineplus.gov/fetalalcoholspectrumdisorders.html</dc:identifier>
<dc:description xml:lang="es">El alcohol puede dañar a su bebé en cualquier etapa del embarazo, inclusive los primeros meses cuando usted quizás todavía no sepa que esta embarazada. Tomar alcohol puede causar un grupo de alteraciones llamadas trastornos del espectro alcohólico fetal. Los efectos en el bebé pueden ser físicos o de comportamiento. Pueden ser problemas con: Aprendizaje y memoria Comprender y seguir instrucciones Control de las emociones Comunicación y socialización Tareas diarias como vestirse o comer El síndrome alcohólico fetal es el tipo de trastorno más serio. Las personas con este síndrome sufren de anormalidades faciales que incluyen ojos muy separados y estrechos, problemas de crecimiento y anomalías del sistema nervioso. El trastorno del espectro alcohólico fetal dura toda la vida. No existe una cura. Los tratamientos pueden ayudar. Estos incluyen medicamentos para tratar los síntomas y terapia de conducta. Estos tratamientos deben ser diferentes para cada persona dependiendo de los síntomas. Centros para el Control y la Prevención de Enfermedades</dc:description>
<dc:description xml:lang="en">Alcohol can harm your baby at any stage during a pregnancy. That includes the earliest stages, before you even know you are pregnant. Drinking during pregnancy can cause a group of conditions called fetal alcohol spectrum disorders (FASDs). Children who are born with FASD can have a mix of problems, such as medical, behavioral, educational, and social problems. The kinds of problems they have depend on which type of FASD they have. The problems could include Abnormal facial features, such as a smooth ridge between the nose and upper lip Small head size Shorter-than-average height Low body weight Poor coordination Hyperactive behavior Difficulty with attention and memory Learning disabilities and difficulty in school Speech and language delays Intellectual disability or low IQ Poor reasoning and judgment skills Sleep and sucking problems as a baby Vision or hearing problems Problems with the heart, kidneys, or bones Fetal alcohol syndrome (FAS) is the most serious type of FASD. People with fetal alcohol syndrome have facial abnormalities, including wide-set and narrow eyes, growth problems and nervous system abnormalities. Diagnosing FASD can be hard because there is no medical test for it. The health care provider will make a diagnosis by looking at the child's signs and symptoms, and will ask whether the mother drank alcohol during pregnancy. FASDs last a lifetime. There is no cure for FASDs, but treatments can help. These include medicines to help with some symptoms, medical care for health problems, behavior and education therapy, and parent training. A good treatment plan is specific to the child's problems. It should include close monitoring, follow-ups, and changes when needed. Certain "protective factors" can help reduce the effects of FASDs and help people who have them reach their full potential. They include Diagnosis before 6 years of age Loving, nurturing, and stable home environment during the school years Absence of violence around them Involvement in special education and social services There is no known safe amount of alcohol during pregnancy. To prevent FASDs, you should not drink alcohol while you are pregnant, or when you might get pregnant. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention</dc:description>
<dc:subject dcterms="mesh">Fetal Alcohol Spectrum Disorders</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Trastornos del espectro alcohólico fetal</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Alcoholismo fetal</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Síndrome de</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Espectro alcohólico fetal</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Trastornos del</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Síndrome de alcoholismo fetal</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">TEAF</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Fetal Alcohol Spectrum Disorders</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="en">FAS</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Fetal Alcohol Syndrome</dc:subject>
</metadata>
</record>
</MedlinePlus-document>
