<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<MedlinePlus-document>
<record>
<header>
<identifier>https://medlineplus.gov/headinjuries.html</identifier>
</header>
<metadata xmlns="http://example.org/myapp/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://example.org/myapp/schema.xsd">
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="es">Cabeza, Lesiones</dc:title>
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="es">Cabeza, Golpes</dc:title>
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="es">Cabeza, Daño</dc:title>
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="en">Skull Injuries</dc:title>
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="en">Cranial Injuries</dc:title>
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="en">Skull Fractures</dc:title>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:language>spa</dc:language>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:title xml:lang="es">Lesiones en la cabeza</dc:title>
<dc:title xml:lang="en">Head Injuries</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>National Library of Medicine</dc:publisher>
<dc:relation type="IsPartOf">Injuries and Wounds</dc:relation>
<dc:date type="created">2011-08-03</dc:date>
<dc:date type="modified">2017-10-02</dc:date>
<dc:identifier type="URL" xml:lang="es">https://medlineplus.gov/spanish/headinjuries.html</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier type="URL" xml:lang="en">https://medlineplus.gov/headinjuries.html</dc:identifier>
<dc:description xml:lang="es">Es probable que usted se haya golpeado la cabeza alguna vez. En general, la lesión es menor ya que el cráneo es duro y protege su cerebro. Pero otras lesiones en la cabeza pueden ser más graves, como una fractura, conmoción cerebral o traumatismo cerebral. Las lesiones en la cabeza pueden ser abiertas o cerradas. Una lesión cerrada no rompe el cráneo. En una lesión abierta, un objeto penetra el cráneo y entra al cerebro. Las lesiones cerradas no siempre son menos graves que las abiertas. Algunas causas comunes de lesiones en la cabeza son las caídas, accidentes de tránsito, violencia o deportes. Es importante conocer las señales de advertencia de las lesiones moderadas a graves. Busque ayuda de inmediato si la persona tiene: Dolor de cabeza que empeora o no mejora Vómitos o nauseas reiteradas Convulsiones Incapacidad para levantarse Pupilas dilatadas en uno o ambos ojos Dificultad para hablar Debilidad o entumecimiento de los brazos o piernas Falta de coordinación Creciente confusión, inquietud o agitación Los médicos usan un examen neurológico y pruebas de imagen para realizar un diagnóstico. El tratamiento depende del tipo de lesión y qué tan grave es. NIH: Instituto Nacional de Trastornos Neurológicos y Accidentes Cerebrovasculares</dc:description>
<dc:description xml:lang="en">Chances are you've bumped your head before. Often, the injury is minor because your skull is hard and it protects your brain. But other head injuries can be more severe, such as a skull fracture, concussion, or traumatic brain injury. Head injuries can be open or closed. A closed injury does not break through the skull. With an open, or penetrating, injury, an object pierces the skull and enters the brain. Closed injuries are not always less severe than open injuries. Some common causes of head injuries are falls, motor vehicle accidents, violence, and sports injuries. It is important to know the warning signs of a moderate or severe head injury. Get help immediately if the injured person has A headache that gets worse or does not go away Repeated vomiting or nausea Convulsions or seizures An inability to wake up Dilated (enlarged) pupil in one or both eyes Slurred speech Weakness or numbness in the arms or legs Loss of coordination Increased confusion, restlessness, or agitation Doctors use a neurologic exam and imaging tests to make a diagnosis. Treatment depends on the type of injury and how severe it is. NIH: National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke</dc:description>
<dc:subject dcterms="mesh">Skull Fractures</dc:subject>
<dc:subject dcterms="mesh">Craniocerebral Trauma</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Lesiones en la cabeza</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Cabeza</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Lesiones</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Cabeza</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Golpes</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Cabeza</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Daño</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Head Injuries</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Skull Injuries</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Cranial Injuries</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Skull Fractures</dc:subject>
</metadata>
</record>
</MedlinePlus-document>
