<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<MedlinePlus-document>
<record>
<header>
<identifier>https://medlineplus.gov/hearthealthtests.html</identifier>
</header>
<metadata xmlns="http://example.org/myapp/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://example.org/myapp/schema.xsd">
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="es">Corazón, Pruebas</dc:title>
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="en">Cardiac Test</dc:title>
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="en">Heart Test</dc:title>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:language>spa</dc:language>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:title xml:lang="es">Pruebas para la salud del corazón</dc:title>
<dc:title xml:lang="en">Heart Health Tests</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>National Library of Medicine</dc:publisher>
<dc:relation type="IsPartOf">Blood, Heart and Circulation</dc:relation>
<dc:date type="created">2017-03-06</dc:date>
<dc:date type="modified">2018-02-07</dc:date>
<dc:identifier type="URL" xml:lang="es">https://medlineplus.gov/spanish/hearthealthtests.html</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier type="URL" xml:lang="en">https://medlineplus.gov/hearthealthtests.html</dc:identifier>
<dc:description xml:lang="es">Las enfermedades del corazón (cardíacas) son la principal causa de muerte en los Estados Unidos y también una causa importante de discapacidad. Si usted tiene enfermedad del corazón, es importante encontrarla temprano, cuando es más fácil de tratar. Los exámenes de sangre y las pruebas de salud del corazón pueden ayudar a encontrarlas o identificar problemas que pueden causarlas. Existen varios tipos diferentes de pruebas de salud del corazón. Su médico decidirá cuáles exámenes o pruebas necesita en base a sus síntomas (si los hay), factores de riesgo y su historia médica. Cateterización cardiaca El cateterismo cardíaco es un procedimiento médico que se utiliza para diagnosticar y tratar algunas enfermedades cardiacas. Para el procedimiento, el médico coloca un catéter (un tubo largo, delgado y flexible) en un vaso sanguíneo en el brazo, la ingle o el cuello y lo dirige hacia el corazón. El médico puede usar el catéter para: Realizar una angiografía coronaria: Esto implica usar un tipo especial de tinte en el catéter, para que fluya por el torrente sanguíneo a su corazón. Luego, su doctor toma radiografías de su corazón. El tinte permite que su médico vea sus arterias coronarias en la radiografía y comprobar si hay enfermedad de las arterias coronarias (acumulación de placa en las arterias) Tomar muestras de sangre y músculo cardíaco Hacer procedimientos como una cirugía del corazón menor o una angioplastía, si el médico lo encuentra necesario Tomografía computarizada del corazón Una tomografía computarizada cardiaca es una prueba de imagen indolora que utiliza rayos X para tomar imágenes claras de su corazón y sus vasos sanguíneos. Las computadoras pueden combinar estas imágenes para crear un modelo tridimensional (3D) de todo el corazón. Esta prueba puede ayudar a los médicos a detectar o evaluar: Enfermedad de las arterias coronarias Acumulación de calcio en las arterias coronarias Problemas de la aorta Problemas con la función cardíaca y las válvulas Trastornos del pericardio Antes de hacerse la prueba, recibirá una inyección de contraste. El tinte destaca su corazón y los vasos sanguíneos en las imágenes. El escáner de la tomografía computarizada es una máquina grande con forma de túnel. Usted permanece acostado sobre una mesa que se desliza en el escáner. La máquina toma las imágenes durante unos 15 minutos. Resonancia magnética cardiaca La resonancia magnética cardíaca es una prueba de imagen indolora que utiliza ondas de radio, imanes y una computadora para crear imágenes precisas de su corazón. Puede ayudar al médico a saber si tiene enfermedad cardiaca, y si es así, su gravedad. Una resonancia magnética cardíaca también puede ayudar a su médico a decidir la mejor forma de tratar problemas cardíacos como: Enfermedad de las arterias coronarias Problemas de válvulas cardíacas Pericarditis Tumores cardíacos Daño por un ataque al corazón La máquina de resonancia magnética es grande y parece un túnel. Usted se acuesta sobre una mesa que le introduce en la máquina. El procedimiento produce un fuerte ruido al tomar fotos de su corazón. El examen tarda entre 30 y 90 minutos. A veces, antes de la prueba, se le puede administrar una inyección de colorante de contraste. Este tinte destaca su corazón y los vasos sanguíneos en las imágenes. Radiografía de pecho La radiografía de pecho toma imágenes de los órganos y estructuras dentro del tórax, como el corazón, los pulmones y los vasos sanguíneos. Puede revelar signos de insuficiencia cardíaca, así como trastornos pulmonares y otras causas de síntomas no relacionados con enfermedades del corazón. Angiografía coronaria La angiografía o angiograma de corazón es un procedimiento que utiliza tintes de contraste y radiografías para observar el interior de las arterias. Puede mostrar si hay placa bloqueando las arterias y qué tan grave es el problema. Los médicos usan esta prueba para diagnosticar enfermedades cardíacas después de dolor en el pecho, un paro cardiaco repentino o resultados anormales de otras pruebas cardíacas, como un electrocardiograma o una prueba de estrés. Por lo general, para aplicar el tinte a sus arterias coronarias se realiza un cateterismo cardíaco. Luego, a usted se le aplican rayos X especiales mientras el tinte fluye por sus arterias coronarias. El tinte permite a su médico estudiar el flujo de sangre a través de su corazón y vasos sanguíneos. Ecocardiografía La ecocardiografía es una prueba indolora que utiliza ondas de sonido para tomar imágenes de su corazón en movimiento. Las imágenes muestran el tamaño y la forma de su corazón. También muestran qué tan bien funcionan las cámaras y válvulas de su corazón. Los médicos usan la ecocardiografía para diagnosticar muchos problemas cardíacos diferentes, y para comprobar lo grave que son. Para la prueba, un técnico aplica gel en su pecho. El gel ayuda a que las ondas de sonido lleguen al corazón. El técnico mueve un transductor (dispositivo parecido a una varita) alrededor de su pecho. El transductor está conectado a una computadora y transmite ondas de ultrasonido en su pecho, las que rebotan produciendo un efecto de eco. La computadora convierte los ecos en imágenes de su corazón. Electrocardiograma Un electrocardiograma es una prueba indolora que detecta y registra la actividad eléctrica de su corazón. Muestra qué tan rápido su corazón late y si el ritmo es constante o irregular. Un electrocardiograma puede ser parte de un examen de rutina para detectar enfermedades del corazón o puede usarse para detectar y estudiar problemas del corazón tales como ataques cardiacos, arritmia e insuficiencia cardíaca. Para la prueba, usted permanece inmóvil sobre una mesa mientras una enfermera o técnico coloca unos electrodos (parches que tienen sensores) sobre la piel de su pecho, brazos y piernas. Los cables conectan los electrodos a una máquina que registra la actividad eléctrica de su corazón. Pruebas de estrés La prueba de estrés examina cómo funciona su corazón durante el esfuerzo físico. Puede ayudar a diagnosticar la enfermedad de las arterias coronarias y comprobar su gravedad. También puede detectar otros problemas como enfermedad de las válvulas cardíacas y la insuficiencia cardíaca. Para la prueba, usted hace ejercicio (o se le administra un medicamento si no puede hacer actividad física) para hacer que su corazón trabaje duro y lata rápido. Mientras esto ocurre, se le aplica un electrocardiograma y se le monitorea la presión arterial. A veces también puede tener un ecocardiograma u otras pruebas de imagen, como una escanografía nuclear. Para la exploración nuclear, se le aplica una inyección de un trazador (una sustancia radiactiva) que se dirige a su corazón. Cámaras especiales detectan la energía del trazador para tomar imágenes de su corazón. Estas fotos se toman después de hacer ejercicio y luego después de descansar. NIH: Instituto Nacional del Corazón, los Pulmones y la Sangre</dc:description>
<dc:description xml:lang="en">Heart diseases are the number one killer in the U.S. They are also a major cause of disability. If you do have a heart disease, it is important to find it early, when it is easier to treat. Blood tests and heart health tests can help find heart diseases or identify problems that can lead to heart diseases. There are several different types of heart health tests. Your doctor will decide which test or tests you need, based on your symptoms (if any), risk factors, and medical history. Cardiac Catheterization Cardiac catheterization is a medical procedure used to diagnose and treat some heart conditions. For the procedure, your doctor puts a catheter (a long, thin, flexible tube) into a blood vessel in your arm, groin, or neck, and threads it to your heart. The doctor can use the catheter to Do a coronary angiography. This involves putting a special type of dye in the catheter, so the dye can flow through your bloodstream to your heart. Then your doctor takes x-rays of your heart. The dye allows your doctor to see your coronary arteries on the x-ray, and to check for coronary artery disease (plaque buildup in the arteries). Take samples of blood and heart muscle Do procedures such as minor heart surgery or angioplasty, if your doctor finds that you need it Cardiac CT Scan A cardiac CT (computed tomography) scan is a painless imaging test that uses x-rays to take detailed pictures of your heart and its blood vessels. Computers can combine these pictures to create a three-dimensional (3D) model of the whole heart. This test can help doctors detect or evaluate Coronary artery disease Calcium buildup in the coronary arteries Problems with the aorta Problems with heart function and valves Pericardial diseases Before you have the test, you get an injection of contrast dye. The dye highlights your heart and blood vessels in the pictures. The CT scanner is a large, tunnel-like machine. You lie still on a table which slides you into the scanner, and the scanner takes the pictures for about 15 minutes. Cardiac MRI Cardiac MRI (magnetic resonance imaging) is a painless imaging test that uses radio waves, magnets, and a computer to create detailed pictures of your heart. It can help your doctor figure out whether you have heart disease, and if so, how severe it is. A cardiac MRI can also help your doctor decide the best way to treat heart problems such as Coronary artery disease Heart valve problems Pericarditis Cardiac tumors Damage from a heart attack The MRI is a large, tunnel-like machine. You lie still on a table which slides you into the MRI machine. The machine makes loud noises as it takes pictures of your heart. It usually takes about 30-90 minutes. Sometimes before the test, you might get an injection of contrast dye. The dye highlights your heart and blood vessels in the pictures. Chest X-Ray A chest x-ray creates pictures of the organs and structures inside your chest, such as your heart, lungs, and blood vessels. It can reveal signs of heart failure, as well as lung disorders and other causes of symptoms not related to heart disease. Coronary Angiography Coronary angiography (angiogram) is a procedure that uses contrast dye and x-ray pictures to look at the insides of your arteries. It can show whether plaque is blocking your arteries and how severe the blockage is. Doctors use this procedure to diagnose heart diseases after chest pain, sudden cardiac arrest, or abnormal results from other heart tests such as an EKG or a stress test. You usually have a cardiac catheterization to get the dye into your coronary arteries. Then you have special x-rays while the dye is flowing through your coronary arteries. The dye lets your doctor study the flow of blood through your heart and blood vessels. Echocardiography Echocardiography, or echo, is a painless test that uses sound waves to create moving pictures of your heart. The pictures show the size and shape of your heart. They also show how well your heart's chambers and valves are working. Doctors use an echo to diagnose many different heart problems, and to check how severe they are. For the test, a technician applies gel to your chest. The gel helps sound waves reach your heart. The technician moves a transducer (wand-like device) around on your chest. The transducer connects to a computer. It transmits ultrasound waves into your chest, and the waves bounce (echo) back. The computer converts the echoes into pictures of your heart. Electrocardiogram (EKG), (ECG) An electrocardiogram, also called an ECG or EKG, is a painless test that detects and records your heart's electrical activity. It shows how fast your heart is beating and whether its rhythm is steady or irregular. An EKG may be part of a routine exam to screen for heart disease. Or you may get it to detect and study heart problems such as heart attacks, arrhythmia, and heart failure. For the test, you lie still on a table and a nurse or technician attaches electrodes (patches that have sensors) to the skin on your chest, arms, and legs. Wires connect the electrodes to a machine that records your heart's electrical activity. Stress Testing Stress testing looks at how your heart works during physical stress. It can help to diagnose coronary artery disease, and to check how severe it is. It can also check for other problems, including heart valve disease and heart failure. For the test, you exercise (or are given medicine if you are unable to exercise) to make your heart work hard and beat fast. While this is happening, you get an EKG and blood pressure monitoring. Sometimes you may also have an echocardiogram, or other imaging tests such as a nuclear scan. For the nuclear scan, you get an injection of a tracer (a radioactive substance), which travels to your heart. Special cameras detect the energy from the tracer to make pictures of your heart. You have pictures taken after you exercise, and then after you rest. NIH: National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute</dc:description>
<dc:subject dcterms="mesh">Diagnostic Techniques, Cardiovascular</dc:subject>
<dc:subject dcterms="mesh">Heart Function Tests</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Pruebas para la salud del corazón</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Corazón</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Pruebas</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Heart Health Tests</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Cardiac Test</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Heart Test</dc:subject>
</metadata>
</record>
</MedlinePlus-document>
