<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<MedlinePlus-document>
<record>
<header>
<identifier>https://medlineplus.gov/howtopreventheartdisease.html</identifier>
</header>
<metadata xmlns="http://example.org/myapp/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://example.org/myapp/schema.xsd">
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="es">Cómo prevenir las enfermedades del corazón</dc:title>
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="es">Prevención de enfermedades del corazón</dc:title>
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="es">Cardíacas, Prevención de enfermedades</dc:title>
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="es">Enfermedades del corazón: Prevención</dc:title>
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="es">Corazón, Prevención de enfermedades de</dc:title>
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="en">Heart Disease Prevention</dc:title>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:language>spa</dc:language>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:title xml:lang="es">Cómo prevenir las enfermedades del corazón</dc:title>
<dc:title xml:lang="en">How to Prevent Heart Disease</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>National Library of Medicine</dc:publisher>
<dc:relation type="IsPartOf">Wellness and Lifestyle</dc:relation>
<dc:relation type="IsPartOf">Blood, Heart and Circulation</dc:relation>
<dc:date type="created">2003-03-12</dc:date>
<dc:date type="modified">2018-02-07</dc:date>
<dc:identifier type="URL" xml:lang="es">https://medlineplus.gov/spanish/howtopreventheartdisease.html</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier type="URL" xml:lang="en">https://medlineplus.gov/howtopreventheartdisease.html</dc:identifier>
<dc:description xml:lang="es">Las enfermedades del corazón son la principal causa de muerte en los Estados Unidos. También es una causa importante de discapacidad. Existen muchas cosas que pueden aumentar su riesgo de sufrir una enfermedad del corazón. Se les llama factores de riesgo. Algunos de ellos no se pueden controlar, pero hay muchos que sí. Aprender sobre ellos puede bajar su riesgo de tener una enfermedad cardíaca. ¿Cuáles son los factores de riesgo de la enfermedad cardíaca que no puedo cambiar? Su edad: Su riesgo de enfermedades del corazón sube a medida que envejece. Los hombres de 45 años o más y las mujeres de 55 años o más tienen un mayor riesgo Sexo: Algunos factores de riesgo pueden afectar de manera diferente a las mujeres comparados con los hombres. Por ejemplo, el estrógeno brinda a las mujeres cierta protección contra las enfermedades del corazón, pero la diabetes aumenta más el riesgo de enfermedades del corazón en las mujeres que en los hombres Raza o etnia: Ciertos grupos tienen mayores riesgos que otros. Los afroamericanos son más propensos que los blancos a tener enfermedades del corazón, mientras que los hispanos son menos propensos a sufrirlas. Algunos grupos asiáticos, como los asiáticos del este, tienen tasas más bajas, pero los asiáticos del sur tienen tasas más altas Historia familiar: Usted tiene un mayor riesgo si tiene un familiar cercano que tuvo una enfermedad cardíaca a una edad temprana ¿Qué puedo hacer para reducir mi riesgo de enfermedad cardíaca? Afortunadamente, hay muchas cosas que usted puede hacer para reducir sus posibilidades de tener enfermedades del corazón: Controle su presión arterial: La presión arterial alta (hipertensión) es un importante factor de riesgo para las enfermedades del corazón. Es importante que su presión arterial sea revisada regularmente, al menos una vez al año para la mayoría de los adultos, y más a menudo si tiene presión arterial alta. Tome medidas para prevenir o controlar la hipertensión, incluyendo cambios en su estilo de vida Mantenga sus niveles de colesterol y triglicéridos bajo control: Los altos niveles de colesterol pueden obstruir sus arterias y aumentar su riesgo de enfermedad coronaria y ataque al corazón. Los triglicéridos son otro tipo de grasa en la sangre. Los altos niveles de triglicéridos en la sangre también pueden aumentar el riesgo de enfermedad coronaria, especialmente en mujeres Mantenga un peso saludable: Tener sobrepeso u obesidad puede aumentar su riesgo de padecer enfermedades cardíacas. Esto es porque están vinculados a otros factores de riesgo de enfermedad del corazón, incluyendo elevados niveles de colesterol y triglicéridos, presión arterial alta y diabetes. Controlar su peso puede reducir estos riesgos Aliméntese con una dieta saludable: Trate de limitar las grasas saturadas, los alimentos ricos en sodio y azúcares agregados. Coma mucha fruta fresca, verduras y granos enteros. La dieta DASH es un ejemplo de un plan de alimentación que puede ayudarle a bajar la presión arterial y el colesterol, lo que puede reducir el riesgo de enfermedades del corazón Haga ejercicio regularmente: El ejercicio tiene muchos beneficios, fortalece su corazón y mejora su circulación. También puede ayudarle a mantener un peso saludable y bajar el colesterol y la presión arterial. Todo esto puede reducir el riesgo de enfermedades del corazón Limite el alcohol: Beber demasiado alcohol puede aumentar su presión arterial y añadir calorías adicionales, lo que puede causar aumento de peso. Ambos aumentan el riesgo de enfermedades del corazón. Los hombres no deben consumir más de dos bebidas alcohólicas al día, y las mujeres no deben tomar más de una No fume: Fumar cigarrillos eleva su presión arterial y lo pone en mayor riesgo de ataque cardíaco y accidente cerebrovascular. Si no fuma, no comience ahora. Si usted fuma, dejar de fumar disminuirá su riesgo de sufrir una enfermedad cardíaca. Usted puede hablar con su médico para que le ayude a encontrar la mejor manera de dejar de fumar Controle el estrés: El estrés está vinculado a las enfermedades del corazón de varias maneras. Puede aumentar la presión arterial. El estrés extremo puede ser un "desencadenante" de un ataque al corazón. Además, algunas maneras comunes de hacer frente al estrés, como comer en exceso, beber mucho y fumar, son dañinas para el corazón. Algunas formas de ayudar a controlar su estrés incluyen hacer ejercicio, escuchar música, enfocarse en algo tranquilo o sereno y meditar Controle la diabetes: Tener diabetes duplica su riesgo de enfermedad cardíaca diabética. Esto se debe a que, con el tiempo, el alto nivel de azúcar en la sangre por la diabetes puede dañar los vasos sanguíneos y los nervios que controlan el corazón y los vasos sanguíneos. Por lo tanto, es importante hacerse la prueba de la diabetes y, si la tiene, mantenerla bajo control Asegúrese de dormir lo suficiente: Si no duerme lo suficiente, aumenta el riesgo de hipertensión, obesidad y diabetes. Estas tres condiciones pueden aumentar su riesgo de enfermedades del corazón. La mayoría de los adultos necesitan de siete a nueve horas de sueño por noche. Asegúrese de tener buenos hábitos de sueño. Si tiene problemas frecuentes para dormir, hable con su proveedor de atención médica. La apnea del sueño, por ejemplo, hace que las personas dejen de respirar brevemente muchas veces durante el sueño. Esto interfiere con su capacidad de obtener un buen descanso y puede aumentar su riesgo de enfermedad cardíaca. Si cree que podría tenerla, pregúntele a su médico si debería realizarse un estudio del sueño. Y si tiene apnea del sueño, asegúrese de recibir tratamiento</dc:description>
<dc:description xml:lang="en">Heart disease is the leading cause of the death in the United States. It is also a major cause of disability. There are many things that can raise your risk for heart disease. They are called risk factors. Some of them you cannot control, but there are many that you can control. Learning about them can lower your risk of heart disease. What are the heart disease risk factors that I cannot change? Age. Your risk of heart disease increases as you get older. Men age 45 and older and women age 55 and older have a greater risk. Gender. Some risk factors may affect heart disease risk differently in women than in men. For example, estrogen provides women some protection against heart disease, but diabetes raises the risk of heart disease more in women than in men. Race or ethnicity. Certain groups have higher risks than others. African Americans are more likely than whites to have heart disease, while Hispanic Americans are less likely to have it. Some Asian groups, such as East Asians, have lower rates, but South Asians have higher rates. Family history. You have a greater risk if you have a close family member who had heart disease at an early age. What can I do to lower my risk of heart disease? Fortunately, there are many things you can do to reduce your chances of getting heart disease: Control your blood pressure. High blood pressure is a major risk factor for heart disease. It is important to get your blood pressure checked regularly - at least once a year for most adults, and more often if you have high blood pressure. Take steps, including lifestyle changes, to prevent or control high blood pressure. Keep your cholesterol and triglyceride levels under control. High levels of cholesterol can clog your arteries and raise your risk of coronary artery disease and heart attack. Lifestyle changes and medicines (if needed) can lower your cholesterol. Triglycerides are another type of fat in the blood. High levels of triglycerides may also raise the risk of coronary artery disease, especially in women. Stay at a healthy weight. Being overweight or having obesity can increase your risk for heart disease. This is mostly because they are linked to other heart disease risk factors, including high blood cholesterol and triglyceride levels, high blood pressure, and diabetes. Controlling your weight can lower these risks. Eat a healthy diet. Try to limit saturated fats, foods high in sodium, and added sugars. Eat plenty of fresh fruit, vegetables, and whole grains. The DASH diet is an example of an eating plan that can help you to lower your blood pressure and cholesterol, two things that can lower your risk of heart disease. Get regular exercise. Exercise has many benefits, including strengthening your heart and improving your circulation. It can also help you maintain a healthy weight and lower cholesterol and blood pressure. All of these can lower your risk of heart disease. Limit alcohol. Drinking too much alcohol can raise your blood pressure. It also adds extra calories, which may cause weight gain. Both of those raise your risk of heart disease. Men should have no more than two alcoholic drinks per day, and women should not have more than one. Don't smoke. Cigarette smoking raises your blood pressure and puts you at higher risk for heart attack and stroke. If you do not smoke, do not start. If you do smoke, quitting will lower your risk for heart disease. You can talk with your health care provider for help in finding the best way for you to quit. Manage stress. Stress is linked to heart disease in many ways. It can raise your blood pressure. Extreme stress can be a "trigger" for a heart attack. Also, some common ways of coping with stress, such as overeating, heavy drinking, and smoking, are bad for your heart. Some ways to help manage your stress include exercise, listening to music, focusing on something calm or peaceful, and meditating. Manage diabetes. Having diabetes doubles your risk of diabetic heart disease. That is because over time, high blood sugar from diabetes can damage your blood vessels and the nerves that control your heart and blood vessels. So, it is important to get tested for diabetes, and if you have it, to keep it under control. Make sure that you get enough sleep. If you don't get enough sleep, you raise your risk of high blood pressure, obesity, and diabetes. Those three things can raise your risk for heart disease. Most adults need 7 to 9 hours of sleep per night. Make sure that you have good sleep habits. If you have frequent sleep problems, contact your health care provider. One problem, sleep apnea, causes people to briefly stop breathing many times during sleep. This interferes with your ability to get a good rest and can raise your risk of heart disease. If you think you might have it, ask your doctor about having a sleep study. And if you do have sleep apnea, make sure that you get treatment for it.</dc:description>
<dc:subject dcterms="mesh">Heart Diseases</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Cómo prevenir las enfermedades del corazón</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Cómo prevenir las enfermedades del corazón</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Prevención de enfermedades del corazón</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Cardíacas</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Prevención de enfermedades</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Enfermedades del corazón: Prevención</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Corazón</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Prevención de enfermedades de</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="en">How to Prevent Heart Disease</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Heart Disease Prevention</dc:subject>
</metadata>
</record>
</MedlinePlus-document>
