<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<MedlinePlus-document>
<record>
<header>
<identifier>https://medlineplus.gov/hiatalhernia.html</identifier>
</header>
<metadata xmlns="http://example.org/myapp/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://example.org/myapp/schema.xsd">
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:language>spa</dc:language>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:title xml:lang="es">Hernia de hiato</dc:title>
<dc:title xml:lang="en">Hiatal Hernia</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>National Library of Medicine</dc:publisher>
<dc:relation type="IsPartOf">Digestive System</dc:relation>
<dc:date type="created">2006-12-22</dc:date>
<dc:date type="modified">2018-01-03</dc:date>
<dc:identifier type="URL" xml:lang="es">https://medlineplus.gov/spanish/hiatalhernia.html</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier type="URL" xml:lang="en">https://medlineplus.gov/hiatalhernia.html</dc:identifier>
<dc:description xml:lang="es">La hernia de hiato es un cuadro en el cual la parte superior del estómago se abulta a través de una abertura en el diafragma. El diafragma es la pared muscular que separa el estómago del tórax. El diafragma ayuda a impedir que el ácido pase hacia el esófago. Cuando existe una hernia hiatal, es más fácil que el ácido suba. El paso del ácido desde el estómago hacia el esófago se denomina reflujo gastroesofágico. El reflujo gastroesofágico puede causar síntomas como: Acidez Problemas para tragar Tos seca Mal aliento Las hernias de hiato son comunes, especialmente en las personas mayores de 50 años. Si tiene síntomas, comer porciones pequeñas, evitar algunos alimentos, no fumar ni beber alcohol y perder peso pueden ayudarlo. El médico puede recomendarle antiácidos u otras medicinas. Si eso no lo ayuda, es posible que sea necesaria una cirugía. NIH: Instituto Nacional de la Diabetes y las Enfermedades Digestivas y Renales</dc:description>
<dc:description xml:lang="en">A hiatal hernia is a condition in which the upper part of your stomach bulges through an opening in your diaphragm. Your diaphragm is the thin muscle that separates your chest from your abdomen. Your diaphragm helps keep acid from coming up into your esophagus. When you have a hiatal hernia, it's easier for the acid to come up. This leaking of acid from your stomach into your esophagus is called GERD (gastroesophageal reflux disease). GERD may cause symptoms such as Heartburn Problems swallowing A dry cough Bad breath Nausea and/or vomiting Breathing problems The wearing away of your teeth Often, the cause of a hiatal hernia is unknown. It may have to do with weakness in the surrounding muscles. Sometimes the cause is an injury or a birth defect. Your risk of getting a hiatal hernia goes up as you age; they are common in people over age 50. You are also at higher risk if you have obesity or smoke. People usually find out that they have a hiatal hernia when they are getting tests for GERD, heartburn, chest pain, or abdominal pain. The tests may be a chest x-ray, an x-ray with a barium swallow, or an upper endoscopy. You don't need treatment if your hiatal hernia does not cause any symptoms or problems. If you do have symptoms, some lifestyle changes may help. They include eating small meals, avoiding certain foods, not smoking or drinking alcohol, and losing weight. Your health care provider may recommend antacids or other medicines. If these don't help, you may need surgery. NIH: National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases</dc:description>
<dc:subject dcterms="mesh">Hernia, Hiatal</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Hernia de hiato</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Hiatal Hernia</dc:subject>
</metadata>
</record>
</MedlinePlus-document>
