<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<MedlinePlus-document>
<record>
<header>
<identifier>https://medlineplus.gov/lymphaticdiseases.html</identifier>
</header>
<metadata xmlns="http://example.org/myapp/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://example.org/myapp/schema.xsd">
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="es">Ganglio linfático</dc:title>
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="es">Sistema linfático, Enfermedades del</dc:title>
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="en">Lymph Nodes</dc:title>
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="en">Swollen Glands</dc:title>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:language>spa</dc:language>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:title xml:lang="es">Enfermedades del sistema linfático</dc:title>
<dc:title xml:lang="en">Lymphatic Diseases</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>National Library of Medicine</dc:publisher>
<dc:relation type="IsPartOf">Immune System</dc:relation>
<dc:date type="created">2002-07-21</dc:date>
<dc:date type="modified">2017-03-22</dc:date>
<dc:identifier type="URL" xml:lang="es">https://medlineplus.gov/spanish/lymphaticdiseases.html</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier type="URL" xml:lang="en">https://medlineplus.gov/lymphaticdiseases.html</dc:identifier>
<dc:description xml:lang="es">El sistema linfático es una red de tejidos y órganos. Está formado principalmente por: Linfa: Un líquido que contiene glóbulos blancos que defienden al cuerpo de los gérmenes Vasos linfáticos: Son los vasos que transportan la linfa por todo el cuerpo, y son distintos a los vasos sanguíneos Ganglios linfáticos: Son glándulas que se encuentran por todos los vasos linfáticos Junto al bazo, estos ganglios son donde los glóbulos blancos luchan contra las infecciones. La médula ósea y el timo producen las células que se encuentran en la linfa. Ambos también son parte de este sistema. El sistema linfático elimina la infección y mantiene el equilibrio de los líquidos del cuerpo. Si no funciona en forma adecuada, el líquido se acumula en los tejidos y causa una hinchazón llamada linfedema. Otros problemas del sistema linfático pueden incluir infecciones, bloqueos y cáncer.</dc:description>
<dc:description xml:lang="en">The lymphatic system is a network of tissues and organs. It is made up of Lymph - a fluid that contains white blood cells that defend against germs Lymph vessels - vessels that carry lymph throughout your body. They are different from blood vessels. Lymph nodes - glands found throughout the lymph vessels. Along with your spleen, these nodes are where white blood cells fight infection. Your bone marrow and thymus produce the cells in lymph. They are part of the system, too. The lymphatic system clears away infection and keeps your body fluids in balance. If it's not working properly, fluid builds in your tissues and causes swelling, called lymphedema. Other lymphatic system problems can include infections, blockage, and cancer.</dc:description>
<dc:subject dcterms="mesh">Lymphatic Diseases</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Enfermedades del sistema linfático</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Ganglio linfático</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Sistema linfático</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Enfermedades del</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Lymphatic Diseases</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Lymph Nodes</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Swollen Glands</dc:subject>
</metadata>
</record>
</MedlinePlus-document>
