<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<MedlinePlus-document>
<record>
<header>
<identifier>https://medlineplus.gov/medicaid.html</identifier>
</header>
<metadata xmlns="http://example.org/myapp/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://example.org/myapp/schema.xsd">
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="es">Seguros</dc:title>
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="en">Insurance</dc:title>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:language>spa</dc:language>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:title xml:lang="es">Medicaid</dc:title>
<dc:title xml:lang="en">Medicaid</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>National Library of Medicine</dc:publisher>
<dc:relation type="IsPartOf">Health System</dc:relation>
<dc:date type="created">2002-07-21</dc:date>
<dc:date type="modified">2017-11-14</dc:date>
<dc:identifier type="URL" xml:lang="es">https://medlineplus.gov/spanish/medicaid.html</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier type="URL" xml:lang="en">https://medlineplus.gov/medicaid.html</dc:identifier>
<dc:description xml:lang="es">Medicaid es un seguro de salud del gobierno estadounidense que ayuda a muchas personas de bajos ingresos en país para pagar sus cuentas médicas. El gobierno federal establece pautas generales para el programa, pero es importante saber que cada estado tiene sus propias reglas. En este sentido, su estado puede requerir que usted pague una parte del costo de algunos servicios médicos. Usted necesita cumplir con ciertos requisitos para recibir ayuda de Medicaid. Entre estos se encuentran: Su edad Si usted está embarazada, es discapacitado o ciego Sus ingresos y recursos Si usted es o no ciudadano de Estados Unidos, y si no, cuál es su estatus migratorio Centro para los Servicios de Medicare y Medicaid</dc:description>
<dc:description xml:lang="en">Medicaid is government health insurance that helps many low-income people in the United States to pay their medical bills. The Federal government sets up general guidelines for the program, but each state has its own rules. Your state might require you to pay a part of the cost for some medical services. You have to meet certain requirements to get Medicaid help. These might involve Your age Whether you are pregnant, disabled, or blind Your income and resources Whether or not you are a U.S. citizen or, if not, what your immigration status is Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services</dc:description>
<dc:subject dcterms="mesh">Medicaid</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Medicaid</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Seguros</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Medicaid</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Insurance</dc:subject>
</metadata>
</record>
</MedlinePlus-document>
