<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<MedlinePlus-document>
<record>
<header>
<identifier>https://medlineplus.gov/medicines.html</identifier>
</header>
<metadata xmlns="http://example.org/myapp/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://example.org/myapp/schema.xsd">
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="es">Información sobre medicinas</dc:title>
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="es">Medicinas, Información sobre las</dc:title>
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="en">Drug Information</dc:title>
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="en">About Your Medicines</dc:title>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:language>spa</dc:language>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:title xml:lang="es">Medicamentos</dc:title>
<dc:title xml:lang="en">Medicines</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>National Library of Medicine</dc:publisher>
<dc:relation type="IsPartOf">Drug Therapy</dc:relation>
<dc:date type="created">2002-07-21</dc:date>
<dc:date type="modified">2017-10-25</dc:date>
<dc:identifier type="URL" xml:lang="es">https://medlineplus.gov/spanish/medicines.html</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier type="URL" xml:lang="en">https://medlineplus.gov/medicines.html</dc:identifier>
<dc:description xml:lang="es">Usted quizás tenga que tomar medicinas todos los días o de vez en cuando. De todas maneras, usted quiere estar seguro de que los medicamentos son seguros y lo van a ayudar a sentirse mejor. En los Estados Unidos, la Administración de Alimentos y Medicamentos (FDA) es la encargada de asegurar la seguridad y efectividad de medicinas con y sin receta. Aún medicamentos seguros pueden causar efectos secundarios o interacciones no deseadas con otros medicamentos o comida que usted esté tomando. Pueden no ser seguros durante el embarazo. Para reducir el riesgo de reacciones y asegurarse de sentirse mejor, es importante que usted tome sus medicinas correctamente y sea cuidadoso al darle medicamentos a los niños.</dc:description>
<dc:description xml:lang="en">You may need to take medicines every day, or only once in a while. Either way, you want to make sure that the medicines are safe and will help you get better. In the United States, the Food and Drug Administration is in charge of assuring the safety and effectiveness of both prescription and over-the-counter medicines. Even safe drugs can cause unwanted side effects or interactions with food or other medicines you may be taking. They may not be safe during pregnancy. To reduce the risk of reactions and make sure that you get better, it is important for you to take your medicines correctly and be careful when giving medicines to children.</dc:description>
<dc:subject dcterms="mesh">Pharmaceutical Preparations</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Medicamentos</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Información sobre medicinas</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Medicinas</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Información sobre las</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Medicines</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Drug Information</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="en">About Your Medicines</dc:subject>
</metadata>
</record>
</MedlinePlus-document>
