<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<MedlinePlus-document>
<record>
<header>
<identifier>https://medlineplus.gov/molds.html</identifier>
</header>
<metadata xmlns="http://example.org/myapp/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://example.org/myapp/schema.xsd">
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:language>spa</dc:language>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:title xml:lang="es">Moho</dc:title>
<dc:title xml:lang="en">Molds</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>National Library of Medicine</dc:publisher>
<dc:relation type="IsPartOf">Poisoning, Toxicology, Environmental Health</dc:relation>
<dc:date type="created">2002-07-21</dc:date>
<dc:date type="modified">2017-07-31</dc:date>
<dc:identifier type="URL" xml:lang="es">https://medlineplus.gov/spanish/molds.html</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier type="URL" xml:lang="en">https://medlineplus.gov/molds.html</dc:identifier>
<dc:description xml:lang="es">El moho está formado por hongos que pueden encontrarse en exteriores o interiores. Crecen mejor en condiciones cálidas, mojadas y húmedas. Si tiene lugares mojados o húmedos en su casa, probablemente tendrá hongos. El moho puede causarle problemas de salud. Inhalar o tocar moho o esporas de moho puede causar reacciones alérgicas o crisis de asma en personas sensibles. También puede causar infecciones micóticas. Además, la exposición al moho puede irritarle los ojos, la piel, la nariz, la garganta y los pulmones. Centros para el Control y la Prevención de Enfermedades</dc:description>
<dc:description xml:lang="en">Molds are fungi that can be found both outdoors and indoors. They grow best in warm, damp and humid conditions. If you have damp or wet spots in your house, you will probably get mold. Molds can cause health problems. Inhaling or touching mold or mold spores may cause allergic reactions or asthma attacks in sensitive people. Molds can cause fungal infections. In addition, mold exposure may irritate your eyes, skin, nose, throat, and lungs. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention</dc:description>
<dc:subject dcterms="mesh">Fungi</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Moho</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Molds</dc:subject>
</metadata>
</record>
</MedlinePlus-document>
