<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<MedlinePlus-document>
<record>
<header>
<identifier>https://medlineplus.gov/pelvicsupportproblems.html</identifier>
</header>
<metadata xmlns="http://example.org/myapp/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://example.org/myapp/schema.xsd">
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="es">Sostén de la pelvis, Problemas de</dc:title>
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="es">Músculos de la pelvis, Problemas de</dc:title>
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="es">Pelvis, Problemas de sostén</dc:title>
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="en">Cystocele</dc:title>
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="en">Uterine Prolapse</dc:title>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:language>spa</dc:language>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:title xml:lang="es">Problemas de sostén de la pelvis</dc:title>
<dc:title xml:lang="en">Pelvic Support Problems</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>National Library of Medicine</dc:publisher>
<dc:relation type="IsPartOf">Female Reproductive System</dc:relation>
<dc:relation type="IsPartOf">Women</dc:relation>
<dc:date type="created">2002-07-21</dc:date>
<dc:date type="modified">2017-07-21</dc:date>
<dc:identifier type="URL" xml:lang="es">https://medlineplus.gov/spanish/pelvicsupportproblems.html</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier type="URL" xml:lang="en">https://medlineplus.gov/pelvicsupportproblems.html</dc:identifier>
<dc:description xml:lang="es">El piso pélvico es un grupo de músculos y otros tejidos que forman una especie de cabestrillo o hamaca a través de la pelvis. En la mujer, mantiene el útero, la vejiga, los intestinos y otros órganos pélvicos en su lugar para que puedan funcionar adecuadamente. Pero el piso pélvico puede debilitarse o lastimarse. Las causas principales son el embarazo y el parto. Otras causas pueden ser la obesidad, tratamientos con radiación, cirugía y envejecimiento. Los síntomas más comunes son: Sensación de pesadez, hinchazón, tirón o dolor en la vagina que se agrava al final del día o cuando mueven el intestino Sensación o ver que un "bulto" o "algo que sale" de la vagina Dificultad para comenzar a orinar o vaciar la vejiga por completo Infecciones del tracto urinario frecuentes Pérdidas de orina al reírse, toser o hacer ejercicio Necesidad urgente o frecuente de orinar Dolor al orinar Pérdidas de materia fecal o dificultad para controlar los gases Estreñimiento Dificultad para llegar al baño a tiempo Su proveedor de cuidados de salud diagnostica este problema con un examen físico, pélvico o pruebas especiales. Los tratamientos incluyen ejercicios pélvicos específicos llamados Kegel; un pesario, que es un dispositivo mecánico de apoyo y le es de ayuda a ciertas mujeres; cirugía y otros tratamientos. NIH: Instituto Nacional de Salud Infantil y Desarrollo Humano</dc:description>
<dc:description xml:lang="en">The pelvic floor is a group of muscles and other tissues that form a sling or hammock across the pelvis. In women, it holds the uterus, bladder, bowel, and other pelvic organs in place so that they can work properly. The pelvic floor can become weak or be injured. The main causes are pregnancy and childbirth. Other causes include being overweight, radiation treatment, surgery, and getting older. Common symptoms include Feeling heaviness, fullness, pulling, or aching in the vagina. It gets worse by the end of the day or during a bowel movement. Seeing or feeling a "bulge" or "something coming out" of the vagina Having a hard time starting to urinate or emptying the bladder completely Having frequent urinary tract infections Leaking urine when you cough, laugh, or exercise Feeling an urgent or frequent need to urinate Feeling pain while urinating Leaking stool or having a hard time controlling gas Being constipated Having a hard time making it to the bathroom in time Your health care provider diagnoses the problem with a physical exam, a pelvic exam, or special tests. Treatments include special pelvic muscle exercises called Kegel exercises. A mechanical support device called a pessary helps some women. Surgery and medicines are other treatments. NIH: National Institute of Child Health and Human Development</dc:description>
<dc:subject dcterms="mesh">Rectal Prolapse</dc:subject>
<dc:subject dcterms="mesh">Rectocele</dc:subject>
<dc:subject dcterms="mesh">Urinary Incontinence, Stress</dc:subject>
<dc:subject dcterms="mesh">Uterine Prolapse</dc:subject>
<dc:subject dcterms="mesh">Pelvic Floor Disorders</dc:subject>
<dc:subject dcterms="mesh">Pelvic Organ Prolapse</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Problemas de sostén de la pelvis</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Sostén de la pelvis</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Problemas de</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Músculos de la pelvis</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Problemas de</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Pelvis</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Problemas de sostén</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Pelvic Support Problems</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Cystocele</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Uterine Prolapse</dc:subject>
</metadata>
</record>
</MedlinePlus-document>
