<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<MedlinePlus-document>
<record>
<header>
<identifier>https://medlineplus.gov/pregnancyandsubstanceabuse.html</identifier>
</header>
<metadata xmlns="http://example.org/myapp/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://example.org/myapp/schema.xsd">
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="es">Fumar durante el embarazo</dc:title>
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="es">Abuso de bebidas alcohólicas durante el embarazo</dc:title>
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="es">Alcohol durante el embarazo, Abuso de</dc:title>
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="es">Drogas, Abuso durante el embarazo</dc:title>
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="en">Substance Abuse in Pregnancy</dc:title>
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="en">Drug Abuse in Pregnancy</dc:title>
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="en">Alcohol Abuse in Pregnancy</dc:title>
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="en">Smoking in Pregnancy</dc:title>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:language>spa</dc:language>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:title xml:lang="es">Abuso de sustancias durante el embarazo</dc:title>
<dc:title xml:lang="en">Pregnancy and Substance Abuse</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>National Library of Medicine</dc:publisher>
<dc:relation type="IsPartOf">Pregnancy and Reproduction</dc:relation>
<dc:relation type="IsPartOf">Substance Abuse Problems</dc:relation>
<dc:relation type="IsPartOf">Female Reproductive System</dc:relation>
<dc:date type="created">2002-07-21</dc:date>
<dc:date type="modified">2018-01-03</dc:date>
<dc:identifier type="URL" xml:lang="es">https://medlineplus.gov/spanish/pregnancyandsubstanceabuse.html</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier type="URL" xml:lang="en">https://medlineplus.gov/pregnancyandsubstanceabuse.html</dc:identifier>
<dc:description xml:lang="es">Cuando se está embarazada no es simplemente "comer por dos." También respira y bebe por dos, de modo que es importante considerar cuidadosamente lo que se le da al bebé. Si fuma o consume alcohol o drogas, también lo hace el feto. En primer lugar, no fume. Si fuma durante el embarazo la nicotina y las sustancias generadoras de cáncer se le pasan al bebé. Fumar también impide que el bebé reciba los nutrientes y aumenta el riesgo de nacimiento sin vida y nacimientos prematuros. No beba alcohol. No se conoce una cantidad de alcohol que sea sana para una mujer embarazada. El alcohol puede causar problemas físicos y de conducta para toda la vida en los niños, inclusive el síndrome de alcoholismo fetal. No consuma drogas ilegales. El consumo de drogas ilegales puede dar como resultado bebés con poco peso, defectos congénitos o síntomas de abstinencia después del nacimiento. Si está embarazada y fuma o consume alcohol o drogas, busque ayuda. El médico puede recomendarle programas para ayudarla a dejar las sustancias. Usted y su bebé estarán mejor sin ellas. Oficina para la Salud de la Mujer en el Departamento de Salud y Servicios Humanos de los EE. UU.</dc:description>
<dc:description xml:lang="en">When you are pregnant, you are not just "eating for two." You also breathe and drink for two, so it is important to carefully consider what you give to your baby. If you smoke, use alcohol or take illegal drugs, so does your unborn baby. First, don't smoke. Smoking during pregnancy passes nicotine and cancer-causing drugs to your baby. Smoke also keeps your baby from getting nourishment and raises the risk of stillbirth or premature birth. Don't drink alcohol. There is no known safe amount of alcohol a woman can drink while pregnant. Alcohol can cause life-long physical and behavioral problems in children, including fetal alcohol syndrome. Don't use illegal drugs. Using illegal drugs may cause underweight babies, birth defects or withdrawal symptoms after birth. If you are pregnant and you smoke, drink alcohol or do drugs, get help. Your health care provider can recommend programs to help you quit. You and your baby will be better off. Dept. of Health and Human Services Office on Women's Health</dc:description>
<dc:subject dcterms="mesh">Pregnancy</dc:subject>
<dc:subject dcterms="mesh">Substance-Related Disorders</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Abuso de sustancias durante el embarazo</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Fumar durante el embarazo</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Abuso de bebidas alcohólicas durante el embarazo</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Alcohol durante el embarazo</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Abuso de</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Drogas</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Abuso durante el embarazo</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Pregnancy and Substance Abuse</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Substance Abuse in Pregnancy</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Drug Abuse in Pregnancy</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Alcohol Abuse in Pregnancy</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Smoking in Pregnancy</dc:subject>
</metadata>
</record>
</MedlinePlus-document>
