<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<MedlinePlus-document>
<record>
<header>
<identifier>https://medlineplus.gov/sarcoidosis.html</identifier>
</header>
<metadata xmlns="http://example.org/myapp/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://example.org/myapp/schema.xsd">
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:language>spa</dc:language>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:title xml:lang="es">Sarcoidosis</dc:title>
<dc:title xml:lang="en">Sarcoidosis</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>National Library of Medicine</dc:publisher>
<dc:relation type="IsPartOf">Lungs and Breathing</dc:relation>
<dc:date type="created">2002-07-21</dc:date>
<dc:date type="modified">2018-01-08</dc:date>
<dc:identifier type="URL" xml:lang="es">https://medlineplus.gov/spanish/sarcoidosis.html</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier type="URL" xml:lang="en">https://medlineplus.gov/sarcoidosis.html</dc:identifier>
<dc:description xml:lang="es">La sarcoidosis es una enfermedad que provoca inflamación, por lo general en sus pulmones, piel y ganglios linfáticos. Comienza como diminutos bultos similares a los granos llamados granulomas. La sarcoidosis puede afectar a cualquier órgano del cuerpo. No se conoce la causa de la sarcoidosis. Afecta a hombres y mujeres de todas las edades y razas. Ocurre sobre todo en personas de 20 a 50 años, los afroamericanos, especialmente mujeres, y las personas de origen de Europa del norte. Muchas personas no tienen síntomas. Si tiene síntomas, éstos pueden incluir: Tos Dificultad para respirar Pérdida de peso Sudores nocturnos Fatiga Los exámenes para diagnosticar la sarcoidosis incluyen radiografías de tórax, pruebas de función pulmonar y una biopsia. No todas las personas con la enfermedad necesitan tratamiento. En el caso de necesitarlo, prednisona, un tipo de esteroide, es el tratamiento principal. NIH: Instituto Nacional del Corazón, los Pulmones y la Sangre</dc:description>
<dc:description xml:lang="en">Sarcoidosis is a disease that leads to inflammation, usually in your lungs, skin, or lymph nodes. It starts as tiny, grain-like lumps, called granulomas. Sarcoidosis can affect any organ in your body. No one is sure what causes sarcoidosis. It affects men and women of all ages and races. It occurs mostly in people ages 20 to 50, African Americans, especially women, and people of Northern European origin. Many people have no symptoms. If you have symptoms, they may include Cough Shortness of breath Weight loss Night sweats Fatigue Tests to diagnose sarcoidosis include chest x-rays, lung function tests, and a biopsy. Not everyone who has the disease needs treatment. If you do, prednisone, a type of steroid, is the main treatment. NIH: National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute</dc:description>
<dc:subject dcterms="mesh">Sarcoidosis</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Sarcoidosis</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Sarcoidosis</dc:subject>
</metadata>
</record>
</MedlinePlus-document>
