<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<MedlinePlus-document>
<record>
<header>
<identifier>https://medlineplus.gov/scoliosis.html</identifier>
</header>
<metadata xmlns="http://example.org/myapp/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://example.org/myapp/schema.xsd">
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:language>spa</dc:language>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:title xml:lang="es">Escoliosis</dc:title>
<dc:title xml:lang="en">Scoliosis</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>National Library of Medicine</dc:publisher>
<dc:relation type="IsPartOf">Bones, Joints and Muscles</dc:relation>
<dc:date type="created">2002-07-21</dc:date>
<dc:date type="modified">2018-01-29</dc:date>
<dc:identifier type="URL" xml:lang="es">https://medlineplus.gov/spanish/scoliosis.html</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier type="URL" xml:lang="en">https://medlineplus.gov/scoliosis.html</dc:identifier>
<dc:description xml:lang="es">La escoliosis causa una curvatura hacia los lados de la columna vertebral o espina dorsal. Las curvas suelen tener forma de S o de C. La escoliosis es más común al final de la niñez y el inicio de la adolescencia, cuando el crecimiento es más rápido. Las niñas suelen tenerla más que los varones. Suele ser hereditaria. Los síntomas incluyen inclinación hacia un lado y tener hombros y caderas desiguales. A veces es fácil notar los síntomas, pero no siempre. Los niños pueden tener un examen para detectar escoliosis en la escuela o durante un chequeo médico. Si parece que hay un problema, los médicos usarán su historial médico y familiar, un examen físico y pruebas de imagen para diagnosticarla. El tratamiento depende de su edad, cuánto más es probable que crezca, cuán marcada es la curva y si la curva es temporal o permanente. Las personas con escoliosis leve pueden necesitar solamente chequeos para ver si la curva está empeorando. Otros podrían necesitar usar un corsé o someterse a una cirugía. NIH: Instituto Nacional de Artritis y Enfermedades Musculoesqueléticas y de la Piel</dc:description>
<dc:description xml:lang="en">Scoliosis causes a sideways curve of your backbone, or spine. These curves are often S- or C-shaped. Scoliosis is most common in late childhood and the early teens, when children grow fast. Girls are more likely to have it than boys. It can run in families. Symptoms include leaning to one side and having uneven shoulders and hips. Sometimes it is easy to notice, but not always. Children may get screening for scoliosis at school or during a checkup. If it looks like there is a problem, your doctor will use your medical and family history, a physical exam, and imaging tests to make a diagnosis. Treatment depends on your age, how much more you're likely to grow, how much curving there is, and whether the curve is temporary or permanent. People with mild scoliosis might only need checkups to see if the curve is getting worse. Others might need to wear a brace or have surgery. NIH: National Institute of Arthritis and Musculoskeletal and Skin Diseases</dc:description>
<dc:subject dcterms="mesh">Scoliosis</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Escoliosis</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Scoliosis</dc:subject>
</metadata>
</record>
</MedlinePlus-document>
