<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<MedlinePlus-document>
<record>
<header>
<identifier>https://medlineplus.gov/teenhealth.html</identifier>
</header>
<metadata xmlns="http://example.org/myapp/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://example.org/myapp/schema.xsd">
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="es">Adolescentes, Salud de los</dc:title>
<dc:title type="alternate" xml:lang="en">Adolescent Health</dc:title>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:language>spa</dc:language>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:title xml:lang="es">Salud de los adolescentes</dc:title>
<dc:title xml:lang="en">Teen Health</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>National Library of Medicine</dc:publisher>
<dc:relation type="IsPartOf">Children and Teenagers</dc:relation>
<dc:relation type="IsPartOf">Population Groups</dc:relation>
<dc:date type="created">2002-08-19</dc:date>
<dc:date type="modified">2018-01-09</dc:date>
<dc:identifier type="URL" xml:lang="es">https://medlineplus.gov/spanish/teenhealth.html</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier type="URL" xml:lang="en">https://medlineplus.gov/teenhealth.html</dc:identifier>
<dc:description xml:lang="es">En la adolescencia pasas por muchos cambios. Tu cuerpo está en camino para alcanzar su tamaño adulto. Puedes notar que no te entran tus zapatos viejos o que los pantalones te quedan siete centímetros más cortos. Además de estos cambios, probablemente te estás haciendo más independiente y tomando más decisiones propias. Algunas de las decisiones más importantes que enfrentas se relacionan con tu salud. Los hábitos saludables, incluyendo una alimentación nutritiva y la actividad física, pueden ayudarte a sentirte bien, verte bien y a esforzarte en la escuela, el trabajo o los deportes. También pueden prevenir enfermedades como la diabetes, la hipertensión arterial, las enfermedades cardiacas, la osteoporosis, los derrames cerebrales y algunos cánceres cuando seas mayor.</dc:description>
<dc:description xml:lang="en">As a teenager, you go through many changes. Your body is on its way to becoming its adult size. You may notice that you can't fit into your old shoes or that your jeans are now 3 inches too short. Along with these changes, you are probably becoming more independent and making more of your own choices. Some of the biggest choices you face are about your health. Healthy habits, including eating a healthy diet and being physically active, can help you feel good, look good, and do your best in school, work, or sports. They might also prevent diseases such as diabetes, high blood pressure, heart disease, osteoporosis, stroke, and some cancers when you are older.</dc:description>
<dc:subject dcterms="mesh">Adolescent Health</dc:subject>
<dc:subject dcterms="mesh">Adolescent, Hospitalized</dc:subject>
<dc:subject dcterms="mesh">Adolescent Health Services</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Salud de los adolescentes</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Adolescentes</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="es">Salud de los</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Teen Health</dc:subject>
<dc:subject xml:lang="en">Adolescent Health</dc:subject>
</metadata>
</record>
</MedlinePlus-document>
